

6 831.331.8276

x sophiahoffman@hotmail.com

github.com/sophiahoffman

in linkedin.com/sophia-hoffman

ABOUT

Previous experience as a Naval officer and finance professional has honed my attention to detail and the ability to hit the ground running. All roads lead to technology and those who don't continually strive to innovate and reinvent themselves will inevitably be left behind. I'm excited to use my broad and complementary skillset and knowledge base in data analytics and software development to implement practical solutions to client challenges.

SKILLS

- REACT
- PYTHON
- DJANGO
- GITHUB
- HTML
- SQL
- CSS
- R
- JSON
- TABLEAU
- HTTP
- CA LICENSED
- JAVASCRIPT
- CPA (INACTIVE)

PROJECTS

ASSETRACKER

Single-page Web-based application using **react** framework; designed to allow users to maintain inventory of high-value assets in a central location specifically for ease of record-keeping for insurance purposes. Styled primarily with **react-bootstrap** and **CSS.** Persistent storage through use of client-side **JSON** database. https://github.com/sophiahoffman/AsseTracker

COFF'ERUP

Full-stack **Python DJANGO** Web application designed to allow multiple users to create and contribute to multiple online digital collection jars. Provides users with the ability to keep track of their contributions and if they have been paid. Styled with **CSS** and some elements of **Bootstrap**. https://github.com/sophiahoffman/CofferUp

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

NORTHWESTERN UNIVERSITY

MASTER OF SCIENCE, ANALYTICS

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN, MADISON

CERTIFICATE IN ACTUARIAL SCIENCE

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY
BACHELOR OF ARTS,
INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

EXPERIENCES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | SEPTEMBER 2019 - MARCH 2020

Intensive full-time, six-month web development bootcamp focused on cultivating the skills and technologies required to become a full-stack software developer:

- Used **Python/Diango** to develop full-stack web applications
- Developed Diango REST API with React front-end
- Git/GitHub for version control and to enable group collaboration; project management tracking with Github Projects
- JavaScript fundamentals using DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Browser-based single-page applications built with react and HTML
- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals
- Group and individual projects reflecting real world team dynamics and problem solving
- Styling using react-bootstrap and CSS
- Nutshell (group project) is a single-page, multi-user app designed to allow users to organize their daily tasks, events, news article, friends, and chat messages. Utilizes react library with react-bootstrap styling and JSON server - individually responsible for articles functionality

DATA ANALYTICS CONSULTANT INTERACTIVE HEALTH | MAY 2016 - APRIL 2018

- Linear regression in **R** to determine major, actionable factors to program participation
- Data visualization for aggregate reporting to clients in **Tableau**

RETAIL ACCOUNTING MANAGER O'NEILL SURF SHOPS | FEBRUARY 2008 - MAY 2013

- Generated consolidated and by store financial statements for multi-million dollar retail enterprise - SAGE MAS 90
- Conducted detailed variance analysis of year over year and actual to budget financials
- Provided operational reports to key decision makers: buyer margin, inventory analysis, sales reports
- Completed California CPA licensure

STAFF AUDITOR

PRICEWATERHOUSE COOPERS | JANUARY 2007 - FEBRUARY 2008

 Participated in audits of publicly traded and pre-IPO companies in the technology and construction sectors

INTELLIGENCE OFFICER US NAVY | OCTOBER 1997 - JULY 2005

- Supported carrier air wing operations by giving pre-mission intelligence briefings and taking detailed post-mission debriefs as the Intelligence Officer for Fighter Squadron 213 (F-14D)
- Developed and conducted training on operational intelligence reporting for the Naval Strike and Air Warfare Center training facility
- Prepared and conducted intelligence briefings on North Korean geopolitical activities to key US and South Korean military officials
- Held Top Secret clearance